{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Mr. W. Simms, the consulting Engineer to the Government of India recommended the gauge for Indian railways", "opta": "1.435 m as adopted in England", "optb": "1.800 m as per Indian conditions", "optc": "1.676 m as a compromise gauge", "optd": "1.000 m as a standard gauge", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If absolute levels of rails at the consecutive axles A, B, and C separated by 1.8 metres are 100.505 m, 100.530 m, and 100.525 m respectively, the unevenness of rails, is", "opta": "0.065 m", "optb": "0.055 m", "optc": "0.045 m", "optd": "0.035 m", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A CST-9 sleeper consists of", "opta": "two inverted triangular pots on either side of rail seat", "optb": "a central plate with a projected key and box on the top of plate", "optc": "a tie bar and 4 cotters to connect two cast iron plates", "optd": "a single two way key provided on the gauge side to hold the rail to sleeper", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Charles Vignoles invented the flat footed rails in", "opta": "1814", "optb": "1836", "optc": "1846", "optd": "1856", "opte": "1873", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To design a cross-over between parallel tracks, the required components are :", "opta": "two switch, points, two acute angle crossings and two check rails", "optb": "two switch points, two acute angle crossings and four check rails", "optc": "two switch points, two acute angle crossings and six check rails", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first Indian railway was laid in", "opta": "1775", "optb": "1804", "optc": "1825", "optd": "1853", "opte": "1876", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The weight of the rails depends upon", "opta": "gauge of the tracks", "optb": "speed of trains", "optc": "spacing of sleepers", "optd": "nature of traffic", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following :", "opta": "Rails are directly laid over hard wooden sleepers and fixed with spikes", "optb": "Adzing is done on hard wooden sleepers", "optc": "Bearing plates are used on soft wooden sleepers", "optd": "Chairs are used for bull headed rails", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "Fish plates fit the underside of the rail head", "optb": "Fish plates fit the top of the rail foot", "optc": "Fish plates fit the web of the rail section", "optd": "Cross sectional area of fish plates, is normally the same as that of the rail section.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Minimum depth of ballast prescribed of B.G. trunk lines of Indian Railways, is", "opta": "20 cm", "optb": "15 cm", "optc": "25 cm", "optd": "30 cm", "opte": "35 cm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Boxing of ballast is done", "opta": "under rails", "optb": "at the rails", "optc": "in between two rails", "optd": "in between two sleepers.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Best ballast contains stones varying in size from", "opta": "1.5 cm to 3 cm", "optb": "2.0 cm to 4 cm", "optc": "2.0 cm to 5 cm", "optd": "2.5 cm to 6 cm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For holding a rail in position, no chairs are used for", "opta": "flat footed rails", "optb": "bull headed rails", "optc": "double headed rails", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Distance between the inner rail and check rail provided on sharp curve, is", "opta": "40 mm", "optb": "42 mm", "optc": "44 mm", "optd": "46 mm", "opte": "50 mm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coal ash (or cinder) is used in initial stages of a new construction of railway for", "opta": "wooden sleepers", "optb": "steel sleepers", "optc": "cast iron sleepers", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pot sleepers are in the form of", "opta": "a number of bowls connected together with a tie bar", "optb": "two bowls placed under each rail and connected together with a tie bar", "optc": "two bowls placed under two rails and the one between the rails", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In railways a triangle is mainly provided for", "opta": "diverting trains from the main line to branch line", "optb": "crossing over between parallel tracks", "optc": "changing direction of engines through 180\u00b0", "optd": "shunting wagons in yards.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A kink is made in stock rails, ahead of the toe of switch at a distance of", "opta": "10 cm", "optb": "15 cm", "optc": "20 cm", "optd": "30 cm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If L is length of a rail and R is the radius of a curve, the versine h for the curve, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rails are bent to correct curvature if the degree of curve, is more than", "opta": "1\u00b0", "optb": "2\u00b0", "optc": "3\u00b0", "optd": "4\u00b0", "opte": "6\u00b0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In India the rails are manufactured by", "opta": "open hearth process", "optb": "duplex process", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "neither (a) nor (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rail section first designed on Indian railways, was", "opta": "double headed", "optb": "bull headed", "optc": "flat footed", "optd": "(a) and (b) simultaneously", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A scissors cross-over consists of", "opta": "two pairs of points, four acute angle crossings and two obtuse angle crossings", "optb": "four pairs of points, four acute angle crossings and four obtuse angle crossings", "optc": "four pairs of points, six acute angle crossings and two obtuse angle crossings", "optd": "two pairs of points, six acute angle crossings and four obtuse angle crossings.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To prevent percolation of water into formation, moorum is used as a blanket for", "opta": "black cotton soil", "optb": "sandy soil", "optc": "clayey soil", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Distance between inner faces of the flanges, is kept", "opta": "equal to the gauge distance", "optb": "slightly less than the gauge distance", "optc": "slightly more than the gauge distance", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wooden sleepers used on the girders of bridges, are generally made of", "opta": "sal", "optb": "chir", "optc": "teak", "optd": "deodar.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If L1 and L2 are actual and theoretical lengths of a tongue rail, d is heel divergence and t is thickness of tongue rail at toe, the switch angle \u03b1 is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If D is distance between centres of two parallel track of gauge G, then, total length of cross-over (from the point of commencement to the point of termination) with an intermediate straight portion and N crossing, is given by", "opta": "DN + G (N + 1 + N2)", "optb": "DN + G (2N + 1 + N2)", "optc": "DN + G (3N + 1 + N2)", "optd": "DN + G (4N + l +N2)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 0.7% upgrade meets a 0.65% downgrade at a summit and the permissible rate of change of grade per chain length is 0.10%, the length of the vertical curve, is", "opta": "10 chains", "optb": "12 chains", "optc": "14 chains", "optd": "16 chains", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Overall depth of a dog spike, is", "opta": "120.6 mm", "optb": "155.90 mm", "optc": "135 mm", "optd": "150 mm", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Best wood for wooden sleepers is", "opta": "chir", "optb": "deodar", "optc": "sal", "optd": "teak", "opte": "shesham.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rail section which is not used on Indian metre gauge tracks, is", "opta": "25 R", "optb": "30 R", "optc": "35 R", "optd": "40 R", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dimensions of a plate girder, are :", "opta": "851 mm x 851 mm", "optb": "255 mm x 254 mm", "optc": "851 mm x 254 mm", "optd": "551 mm x 254 mm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rail joint supported on a single sleeper, is known", "opta": "suspended rail joint", "optb": "bridge rail joint", "optc": "supported rail joint", "optd": "square rail joint.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maximum wheel base distance provided on Indian B.G. tracks, is", "opta": "4.096 m", "optb": "5.096 m", "optc": "6.096 m", "optd": "7.096 m", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The tread of wheels is provided an outward slope of", "opta": "1 in 10", "optb": "1 in 15", "optc": "1 in 20", "optd": "1 in 25", "opte": "1 in 30", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On a straight railway track, absolute levels at point A on two rails are 100.550 m and 100.530 m and the absolute levels at point B 100 m apart are 100.585 m and 100.515 m respectively, the value of twist of rails per metre run, is", "opta": "0.4 mm", "optb": "0.5 mm", "optc": "0.7 mm", "optd": "0.8 mm", "opte": "1.0 mm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bearing plates are used to fix", "opta": "flat footed rails to the wooden sleepers", "optb": "double headed rails to the wooden sleepers", "optc": "bull headed rails to the wooden sleepers", "optd": "flat footed rails to the cast iron sleepers", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A welded rail joint is generally", "opta": "supported on a sleeper", "optb": "supported on a metal plate", "optc": "suspended", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Safe speed (V) on a curve of radius 970 metres provided with two transition curves on Board Gauge track, is", "opta": "112 km/hour", "optb": "122 km/hour", "optc": "132 km/hour", "optd": "142 km/hour", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "Sleepers hold the rails at proper gauge on straights", "optb": "Sleepers provide stability to the permanent way", "optc": "Sleepers act as an elastic cushion between rails and ballast", "optd": "Sleepers transfer load of moving trains to ballast", "opte": "None of the these.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If \u03b1 is switch angle and R is radius of the turnout, the length of the tongue rail, is", "opta": "R sin \u03b1", "optb": "R tan \u03b1", "optc": "R sin \u03b1/2", "optd": "R tan \u03b1/2", "opte": "R cos \u03b1/2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The quantity of stone ballast required per metre tangent length, is", "opta": "1.15 m3", "optb": "1.14 m3", "optc": "1.13 m3", "optd": "1.12 m3", "opte": "1.11 m3", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The type of switch generally used for B.G. and M.G. tracks, is", "opta": "articulated", "optb": "undercut", "optc": "over riding", "optd": "straight cut.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference in the lengths of two diagonals of a rail diamond is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For flat bottom sleepers, maximum size of ballast, is", "opta": "50 mm", "optb": "40 mm", "optc": "33 mm", "optd": "25 mm", "opte": "20 mm", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coning of wheels", "opta": "prevent lateral movement of wheels", "optb": "provide smooth running of trains", "optc": "avoid excessive wear of inner faces of rail", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sleepers which satisfy the requirements of an ideal sleeper, are", "opta": "cast iron sleepers", "optb": "R.C.C. sleepers", "optc": "steel sleepers", "optd": "wooden sleepers.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Arrangement made to divert the trains from one track to another, is known as", "opta": "railway point", "optb": "railway crossing", "optc": "turnout", "optd": "railway junction", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At a rail joint, the ends of adjoining rails, are connected with a pair of fish plates and", "opta": "2 fish bolts", "optb": "4 fish bolts", "optc": "6 fish bolts", "optd": "8 fish bolts", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}